# Nicholas Howard

nickhoward.dev ❖ nhowar@uwo.ca ❖ (581) 922-3342 ❖ London, ON

# **Objective**

Creative and diligent computer science student with well developed technical proficiency that builds upon six years of managerial experience in the reclamation industry. I am eager to apply my technical skills as well as teamwork and problem solving abilities to projects in software development.

#### Education

University of Western Ontario 2021 - present Honors Specialization in Computer Science - London, Ontario

- Dean's Honor List 2021, 2022, & 2023
- Maintained an average of 89%

#### **Technical Skills**

- Object Oriented Programming in Python, Java, and C.
- MySQL & Database Management
- Linux Bash and package management
- HTML & CSS
- GitHub and Version Control
- Jira, Confluence

### **Projects**

- LogicLand An educational app that teaches formal logic and foundational computer science concepts through the use of logic gates. Completed as a group project for Western in which I was responsible for the user interface and collaborated with another member on the logic circuits. Programmed in Java using JavaFX.
  - A demonstration can be found here <a href="https://www.voutube.com/watch?v=51Ki6Te4YFs">https://www.voutube.com/watch?v=51Ki6Te4YFs</a>
  - The code can be found here https://github.com/readygroup1/LogicLand

#### Soft Skills

- Leadership
  - O As a Manager at Little Smokey, I was responsible for hiring, training and daily management of a crew of up to eleven planters in the reforestation of previously logged land in Northern Alberta. Each summer my crew and I would plant approximately a million trees and reclaim over 700 hectares of land.
- Analytical Thinking and Logistics
  - At Little Smokey, I planned and executed daily deliveries of tens of thousands of seedlings by various means such as ATV and via helicopter. I would analyze the map to ensure that the correct tree species was planted into the correct type of land for each of my planters.

## Work Experience

• Little Smokey Forestry Services - Foreman - Grande Prairie, AB May 2017 - August 2022

Whistler Blackcomb - Logistics associate - Whistler, BC
Gentech Roofing - Mississauga, ON
September 2016 - May 2017
August 2015 - September 2016

• Summit Screen Printing Supplies - Penticton, BC October 2013— August 2015

• Assisted in the purchase, relocation, and modernization of a distribution business.